SAMUEL JOSEPH THOMPSON

17630 Lomond Blvd, Shaker Heights, OH, 44120

Phone: 216.970.1203 ■ E-Mail: thomps9012@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-joseph-thompson/ Github: https://github.com/thomps9012

Portfolio: https://thomps9012.github.io/ThompsonPortfolio/

Full Stack Web Developer with experience working in a remote environment alongside individuals from a diverse set of backgrounds with client, server, database, and systems engineering experience. I enjoy learning new practices and applying them to solve novel challenges and problems that arise within the work environment. Thank you for the opportunity to bring a dedicated work ethic and commitment of excellence to your team.

Technical Skills

<u>Languages & Libraries:</u> HTML, AJAX, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, Python, Node.js, HTTP, ReST API, GitHub, Express.js, Sequelize, No SQL, MongoDB

<u>Frameworks & Concepts:</u> Responsive Design, Object Oriented Programming, Test Driven Development, Express.js, Node Test-Driven Development

Projects

Trail Tails | https://github.com/evigliucci/project1 | https://evigliucci.github.io/project1/

- A web-based application that helps users find local trails using geolocation or a typed in location. The application will return ten different hiking options based off user preferences once a selection is made the app shows weather and trail conditions.
- Creator of the idea and vision of the project helped connect the hiking trails API calls as well as worked on a portion of the front-end web development.
- HTML (Bootstrap and Custom), CSS/SCSS, JavaScript (jQuery and Custom), APIs (Google Maps, OpenWeather, and Hiking Project), and Local Storage

Notetaker App | https://github.com/thomps9012/NoteTaker | https://radiant-cliffs-00329.herokuapp.com/

- A notetaker app that allows users to create, save, and delete notes using My SQL. The application uses a local host set up to run the application.
- Created the application from scratch, using GitHub for commits, and Heroku to host the final live application.
- HTML, CSS, JSON, SQL, and API routes

Calendar App | https://github.com/thomps9012/CalendarHW | https://thomps9012.github.io/CalendarHW/

- A daily schedule application that utilizes JavaScript, CSS, and HTML in order to save typed in tasks to local storage. The app automatically changes color of the hour based on whether the hour has passed (green for current or future hours and red for past hours).
- Created the application from scratch, using GitHub for commits, and Heroku to host the final live application.
- HTML, CSS, JSON, SQL, and jQuery were used for this application

ST

Work Experience

Elementary Science Teacher Clark County School District

Las Vegas, NV

August 2016 – Spring 2019

- Admitted to a highly selective cohort of recent college graduates and career changers committed to raising student achievement in Clark County School District's highest need schools
- Experience working in a personalized learning environment, regularly managing classrooms comprised of anywhere from 30 – 39 pupils
- Worked with students from a diverse set of backgrounds and experiences and helped students achieve academic success by leveraging their unique experiences to increase their knowledge base

Student Senator

The Associated Students of The University of Montana (ASUM)

Missoula, MT

April 2013 - May 2014

- Gained leadership skills while creating tangible and effective change on campus issues, such as sustainable campus transportation
- Further developed networking abilities and capacity to work with individuals across the political spectrum
- Through my work as an ASUM Senator I garnered a deeper understanding of the importance of equal education opportunities

Yellow Bicycle Share Program Manager

Associated students of The University of Montana Transportation (ASUM)

Missoula, MT

August 2013 – July 2014

- Managed distribution of a free bicycle rental service to students on campus providing a sustainable transportation service around town
- Responsible for maintenance, repair, and organization of bicycles to ensure student access to free bicycle rentals during school semesters
- Administrative tasks included emailing and calling semester bike renters and promoting Yellow Bicycle Program throughout campus
- I established the first recorded metrics of bike rental usage per semester

Education

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Case Western Reserve University

Cleveland, OH

February 2020 – August 2020

- Funded partly by AmeriCorps Award
- Learning both back and front-end web development

Bachelor's Degree

The University of Montana

Missoula, MT

Autumn 2012 - Winter 2015

- Recipient of a departmental scholarship
- Environmental Studies Bachelor of Arts

Program Graduate National Outdoor Leadership School (NOLS)

Tucson, Arizona

Autumn 2011 - Winter 2011

- Graduated with a Leave No Trace Masters Certificate
- Was identified as a candidate for a NOLS Instructor Course
- Gained valuable leadership experience in the field

Awards

Leadership, Achievement, and Service Scholarship The University of Montana

Missoula, MT

Autumn 2012 – Winter 2015

 Award based on participation and graduation from the National Outdoor Leadership School's Semester in the Southwest program

Kain-McKay Scholarship The University of Montana

Missoula, MT

Autumn 2013 - Winter 2015

• Scholarship received based on lobbying and internship experience with The Montana Public Interest Research Group on environmental issues in the state of Montana